<topics>
<top>

<num>302 </num> 
<title> poliomyelitis and post polio </title>

<desc> Description: 
Is the disease of Poliomyelitis (polio) under control in the
world?
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents should contain data or outbreaks of the 
polio disease (large or small scale), medical protection 
against the disease, reports on what has been labeled as 
"post-polio" problems.  Of interest would be location of 
the cases, how severe, as well as what is being done in 
the "post-polio" area.
</narr> 
</top>

<top>

<num>308 </num> 
<title> implant dentistry </title> 

<desc> Description: 
What are the advantages and/or disadvantages of tooth implants?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A tooth replacement procedure, begun in the 1960s by Doctor
Branemark, is becoming more widely used today.  It involves 
the replacement of a lost tooth/teeth by an implantation 
process which secures the fabricated tooth to a titanium post
with an adhesive resulting in a stable and sturdy denture 
almost like the original.  A relevant document will include 
any clinical experiment, report, study, paper, or medical 
discussion which describes the advantages or disadvantages of 
tooth implant(s), conditions under which such a procedure is 
favorable, denture comfort and function compared to false teeth, 
bridge, or plate and comparative cost differential.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>310 </num>
<title> radio waves and brain cancer </title> 

<desc> Description: 
Evidence that radio waves from radio towers or car phones affect
brain cancer occurrence.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Persons living near radio towers and more recently persons using
car phones have been diagnosed with brain cancer.  The argument 
rages regarding the direct association of one with the other.
The incidence of cancer among the groups cited is considered, by
some, to be higher than that found in the normal population.  A 
relevant document includes any experiment with animals, statistical 
study, articles, news items which report on the incidence of brain 
cancer being higher/lower/same as those persons who live near a 
radio tower and those using car phones as compared to those in the 
general population.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>333 </num>
<title> antibiotics bacteria disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
Determine the reasons why bacteria seems to be winning
the war against antibiotics and rendering antibiotics
now less effective in treating diseases than they were
in the past.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will address the questions of how 
and why, and to what degree, bacteria are able to fend 
off the curative effects of antibiotics.  Overuse of 
antibiotics, as well as the increasing use of antibiotics
in promoting the growth of crops and animals whose food
products are meant for human consumption have played roles
in creating a situation where every known bacteria-generated
disease now has versions that resist at least one of the 
more than 100 antibiotics now in use.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>335 </num>
<title> adoptive biological parents </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify the problems, and solutions to those problems, 
which arise in the relationships among biological
parents, adoptive parents, and the child or children 
involved.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will report on court procedures 
and decisions which affect the rights of biological
parents, adoptive parents, as well as the adopted 
child.  Problems arise when the biological parents 
of a child given up for adoption decide that they 
or he/she would like to reclaim the child against 
the wishes of the adoptive parents.  Problems also 
arise when the adopted child tries to identify and
contact the biological parents, but find the way
blocked by sealed court orders.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>337 </num>
<title> viral hepatitis </title>

<desc> Description: 
What research has been done on viral hepatitis 
and what progress has been made in its treatment?
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document might include any of the 
following information: 

-- A medical procedure used in the treatment of
   hepatitis.

-- Ongoing research in vaccines, including the 
   identity of the strain of hepatitis.

-- How hepatitis affects the body's immune system.

-- Third World countries' reports on control of
   the disease.
</narr>
</top>


<top>

<num>338 </num>
<title> risk of aspirin </title>

<desc> Description: 
What adverse effects have people experienced while taking 
aspirin repeatedly?
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document should identify any adverse effects 
experienced from the repeated use of aspirin. Possible 
effects might include intestinal bleeding, inflammation 
of the stomach, or various forms of ulcers. The purpose 
of the individual's repeated aspirin use should also 
be stated.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num> 339 </num>
<title> Alzheimers drug treatment </title>

<desc> Description: 
What drugs are being used in the treatment of 
Alzheimer's Disease and how successful are they?
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document should name a drug used in 
the treatment of Alzheimer's Disease and also 
its manufacturer, and should give some indication 
of the drug's success or failure.
</narr> 
</top>

<top>

<num>349 </num>
<title> metabolism </title>

<desc> Description: 
Document will discuss the chemical reactions 
necessary to keep living cells healthy and/or
producing energy.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will contain specific information
on the catabolic and anabolic reactions of the metabolic
process.  Relevant information includes, but is not 
limited to, the reactions occurring in metabolism, 
biochemical processes (Glycolysis or Krebs cycle for
production of energy), and disorders associated with 
the metabolic rate.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>356 </num>
<title> postmenopausal estrogen Britain </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents discussing the use of estrogen by 
postmenopausal women in Britain. 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The use of hormone replacement therapy outside of the United 
Kingdom is not relevant.  United Kingdom and British 
development and marketing of estrogen suppressing 
drugs are relevant.   
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>364 </num>
<title> rabies </title> 

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents discussing cases where rabies
have been confirmed and what, if anything, is 
being done about it.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies confirmed cases 
of rabies and may contain actions taken to correct 
the problem.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num> 366 </num>
<title> commercial cyanide uses </title>

<desc> Description: 
What are the industrial or commercial uses of 
cyanide or its derivatives? 
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A document is relevant if it names or describes a 
process that uses cyanide commercially or mentions
that cyanide-rich waste comes from a particular
industry.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>368 </num>
<title> in vitro fertilization </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents that discuss in vitro
fertilization.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will describe any aspect
of the process of in vitro fertilization:
uniting two human germ cells (sperm and egg)
outside of the human body and in an artificial
environment.   Documents that describe related 
techniques, such as the freezing of eggs, 
sperm, or embryos for future implantation are
also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>369 </num>
<title> anorexia nervosa bulimia </title>

<desc> Description: 
What are the causes and treatments of anorexia nervosa
and bulimia?
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will describe the causes of the 
eating disorders, anorexia nervosa or bulimia.
Documents that describe symptoms including the taking of 
laxatives, self-induced vomiting and excessive exercise 
are relevant.  Discussions of the treatment of the 
disorders are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>371 </num>
<title> health insurance holistic </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is the extent of health insurance coverage of 
holistic or other non-traditional medicine/medical treatments
(for example, acupuncture)?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Discussions of whether or not particular health insurance
plans cover alternative treatments are relevant.  Discussions
of coverage for preventative programs such as health 
education or wellness sessions are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>380 </num>
<title> obesity medical treatment </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents that discuss medical treatment
of obesity. 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document should identify prescribed
legal medications or treatments used to combat
obesity and the positive or negative affects
resulting from the applications.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num> 381 </num>
<title> alternative medicine </title>

<desc> Description: 
What forms of alternative medicine are being
used in the treatment of illnesses or diseases
and how successful are they?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document should identify a form of
alternative medicine which is being utilized 
in the treatment of a disease or illness, 
identify the illness or disease being treated,
and provide an indication of the success of the
procedure.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>383 </num>
<title> mental illness drugs </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify drugs used in the treatment of mental illness.  
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will include the name of a specific
or generic type of drug.  Generalities are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>390 </num>
<title> orphan drugs </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find documents that discuss issues associated with so-called 
"orphan drugs", that is, drugs that treat diseases affecting 
relatively few people.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss how the Orphan Drug Act 
is working on behalf of those who suffer from orphan 
diseases and conditions, or how this matter is handled in 
other countries.
</narr> 
</top>


<top>

<num>391 </num>
<title> RD drug prices </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents that discuss the impact of the cost of research
and development (RD) on the price of drugs.  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that describe how any aspect of the development of a drug
affects its price are relevant.  Documents that discuss other factors
that affect drug prices, such as advertising, without also discussing
RD costs, are not relevant.
</narr>
 
</top>


<top>

<num>396</num>
<title> sick building syndrome </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify documents that discuss sick building syndrome or
building-related illnesses.
</desc> 
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document would contain any data that refers to 
the sick building or building-related illnesses, including
illnesses caused by asbestos, air conditioning, pollution
controls.  Work-related illnesses not caused by the building,
such as carpal tunnel syndrome, are not relevant.
</narr> 
</top>


<top>

<num>402 </num> 
<title> behavioral genetics </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is happening in the field of behavioral genetics,
the study of the relative influence of genetic
and environmental factors on an individual's behavior
or personality?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing genetic or environmental factors relating
to understanding and preventing substance abuse and addictions
are relevant.  Documents pertaining to attention deficit disorders
tied in with genetics are also relevant, as are genetic disorders 
affecting hearing or muscles.  The genome project is relevant
when tied in with behavior disorders (i.e., mood disorders,
Alzheimer's disease). 
</narr>
</top>


<top>

<num>403 </num>
<title> osteoporosis </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find information on the effects of the dietary intakes
of potassium, magnesium and fruits and vegetables as
determinants of bone mineral density in elderly men
and women thus preventing osteoporosis (bone decay). 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document may include one or more of the
dietary intakes in the prevention of osteoporosis.
Any discussion of the disturbance of nutrition and
mineral metabolism that results in a decrease in 
bone mass is also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>406 </num> 
<title> Parkinsons disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
What is being done to treat the symptoms of 
Parkinson's disease and keep the patient 
functional as long as possible?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies a drug or treatment 
program utilized in patient care and provides 
an indication of success or failure.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>427</num>
<title> uv damage eyes </title>

<desc> Description: 
Find documents that discuss the damage ultraviolet (UV)
light from the sun can do to eyes.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss diseases that result
from exposure of the eyes to UV light, treatments
for the damage, and/or education programs that help
prevent damage.  Documents discussing treatment
methods for cataracts and ocular melanoma are relevant
even when a specific cause is not mentioned.  However,
documents that discuss radiation damage from nuclear
sources or lasers are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>


<top>

<num>429 </num>
<title> legionnaires disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
Identify outbreaks of Legionnaires' disease.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss a specific outbreak
of Legionnaires' disease.  Documents that address prevention of
or cures for the disease without citing a specific case are 
not relevant.
</narr>
</top>


<top>

<num>441 </num>
<title> lyme disease </title>

<desc> Description: 
How do you prevent and treat Lyme disease?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss current prevention and
treatment techniques for Lyme disease are
relevant.  Reports of research on new
treatments of the disease are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>

<num>449 </num>
<title> antibiotics ineffectiveness </title>

<desc> Description: 
What has caused the current ineffectiveness of
antibiotics against infections and what is
the prognosis for new drugs?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss the reasons or 
causes for the ineffectiveness of current antibiotics.
Relevant documents may also include efforts by pharmaceutical
companies and federal government agencies to find new cures, 
updating current testing phases, new drugs being tested,
and the prognosis for the availability of new and effective
antibiotics. 
</narr>
</top>


<top>
<num>604 </num>
<title> Lyme disease arthritis </title>

<desc> Description:
What evidence is there to link tick-borne Lyme disease with arthritis?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
Documents providing evidence to support or refute the connection
between Lyme disease and arthritis are relevant.  Documents discussing
Lyme disease and inflammatory joint disorder are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>


<top>
<num>605 </num>
<title> Great Britain health care </title>

<desc> Description:
What are the pros and cons of Great Britain's universal health
care system?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
Documents that discuss recommendations for change or list criticisms
of the current system are relevant.  Documents about an individual's
experience with the health care system in Great Britain are irrelevant
unless the document also contains a specific recommendation or criticism.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>607 </num>
<title> human genetic code </title>

<desc> Description:
What progress is being made in the effort to map and sequence
the human genetic code?
</desc>

<narr> Narrative:
Documents must discuss specific progress in mapping the
human genome.  Documents that simply describe applications of
the research, such as using DNA in criminal cases,
using the genetic code to treat disease, or creating
genetically engineered organisms are irrelevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>630 </num>
<title> Gulf War syndrome </title>

<desc> Description:
Retrieve documents containing information about the symptoms
of individuals suffering from 'Gulf War Syndrome' as a result
of serving in the Gulf War.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
Documents regarding law suits that claim causes of illness from service
in the Gulf War are relevant, as are reports of cases resulting from
contact with an ill Gulf War veteran.  'Dessert Storm Syndrome' is
a synonym for the condition and is considered relevant.
</narr>
</top>


<top>
<num>634 </num>
<title> l tryptophan deaths </title>

<desc> Description:
How many deaths are attributed to having taken tainted L-tryptophan
dietary supplements?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
A relevant document will describe a specific case of death attributed to
tainted L=tryptophan or will give figures regarding total
number of deaths.  Reports of illness caused by the supplement
that did not result in death are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>635 </num>
<title> doctor assisted suicides </title>

<desc> Description:
What are the arguments for and against doctor assisted suicide in the U.S.?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must contain a viewpoint regarding doctor
assisted suicide to be relevant.  Reports describing actual
doctor assisted suicides are not relevant unless the document
also presents a pro or con argument.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>637 </num>
<title> human growth hormone HGH </title>

<desc> Description:
What are the pros and cons of adults using human growth hormone (HGH)?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative:
A relevant document must discuss a specific application of human growth
hormone in adults.  Documents about using growth hormone to help
short children are irrelevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>640 </num>
<title> maternity leave policies </title>

<desc> Description:
What are the maternity leave policies of various governments?
</desc>

<narr> Narrative:
Relevant documents will contain specific details about a
legally-mandated maternity leave policy.  Current or passed
legislation is relevant, but proposed or in-process legislation is not.
Vetoes of bills for maternity leave are irrelevant.  Legislation that
is passed, but not yet enacted (i.e. to take effect at a specific
time in future) is relevant.  Issues of cost to businesses and/or
government are irrelevant.  Statements to the effect of what benefits
are not provided are relevant.
</narr>  
</top>

<top>
<num>655 </num>

<title> ADD diagnosis treatment </title>

<desc>
How is Attention Deficit Disorder (ADD) diagnosed and treated in
young children?
</desc>

<narr>
Relevant documents specifically address diagnosis and/or treatment
of ADD.  Simple definitions and descriptions of ADD are not relevant.
Documents that discuss studies that could lead to treatment are relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>656 </num>
<title> lead poisoning children </title>

<desc>
How are young children being protected against lead poisoning from paint
and water pipes?
</desc>

<narr>
Documents describing the extent of the problem, including
suits against manufacturers and product recalls, are relevant.
Descriptions of future plans for lead poisoning abatement projects
are also relevant.  Worker problems with lead are not relevant.  Other
poison hazards for children are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>


<top>

<num>661 </num>

<title> melanoma treatment causes </title>

<desc>
What are the causes and treatments for melanoma?
</desc>
<narr>
Relevant documents describe causes, diagnosis, and/or treatment of
melanoma.  Articles on research being conducted that could lead to
diagnosis or treatment are also relevant.  Articles on other diseases,
including other skin cancers, are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>668 </num>

<title> poverty disease </title>

<desc>
What is the relationship between poverty and disease?
</desc>
<narr>
Documents that do not link poverty to diseases directly but mention a
link between poverty and health care are relevant. Documents that simply
mention poverty and disease but do not draw a connection are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>692 </num>

<title> prostate cancer detection treatment </title>

<desc>
Find information on prostate cancer detection and treatment.
</desc>
<narr>
Different kinds of treatment are relevant, but only when tied to
prostate cancer.  The affliction or treatment of a particular
(well-known) individual is not relevant, nor is treatment or detection
of benign prostate enlargement (BHP).
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>696 </num>

<title> safety plastic surgery </title>

<desc>
Find documents that discuss the safety of or the hazards of cosmetic
plastic surgery.
</desc>

<narr>
Relevant document must refer to a safety issue regarding an elective
cosmetic procedure performed for enhancement of an individual's body
image.
</narr>
</top>
</topics>
